# **ARULJOTHI PARTHIBAN**

Full Stack Developer & Lead



# **HELLO**

I am Aruljothi Parthiban, a determined and solution-focused full-stack developer and lead with eight years of experience in the development, enhancement, and troubleshooting of complex web applications that support large, scalable, and distributed systems.

I am an intuitive problem-solver who demonstrates the ability to learn and master new and emerging technologies while working in both teams and self-directed settings.

# **EXPERIENCE**

ASP.NET MVC	8 Years
WEB API	5 Years
NODE JS	6 Years
JAVASCRIPT	8 Years
REACT + REDUX	4 Years
ANGULAR 1.0	4 Years
SQL SERVER	8 Years
Mongo DB	6 Years
HTML 5 + CSS 3	8 Years

#### CONTACT

П

+91 8189981738 aruljothiparthiban@hotmail.com

No 26/1, 2<sup>nd</sup> Main Road, Venkateshwara Nagar, Ramapuram, Chennai - 600089

https://github.com/aruljothiparthiban

# **EMPLOYMENT**

Photon Infotech Pvt Ltd

Feb 2018 - Present

#### **Module Lead**

- Developed a single page web application to manage campaigns and offers for e-commerce vendors.
- Developed micro-services on top of Express and Mongo Db stack.
- Written unit testing for React using Enzyme and used Mocha and Chai for back-end code.
- Written functional test cases using Cucumber and used Pact for contract testing micro-services.
- Deployed software to production and non-production environments using Jenkins. Led effects to improve software quality.

Universal Power Systems Pvt Ltd

Jan 2014 - Feb 2018

#### **Module Lead**

- Developed a mobile recharge and bill payment portal for Aircel users.
- Constructed a reporting tool so that administrator, circle administrator and customer support agent in Aircel could see their user's transactions progress in real time.
- Developed an Identity Provider application by implementing OAuth and Open ID Connect protocol to authenticate/authorize all in-house applications.
- Built a web application to send a traffic conversion details to Ad Publisher platform from Wap platform.
- Developed a free entertainment video streaming web application.
- Developed a single page web application to create web pages to market digital contents to users via telecommunication operators.
- Deployed software to production and non-production environments using Jenkins. Worked using the Agile methodology with daily stand-ups and weekly sprints.

Ibox Technology Pvt Ltd

May 2012 - Nov 2013

#### **Assistant Project Leader**

- Created single page web application for booking, managing and tracking shipping containers for the Mediterranean Shipping Company (MSC).
- ❖ Introduced the ASP.NET MVC framework and Knockout within the organization and mentored the team to use it.
- Followed the Test Driven Development (TDD) for delivering better quality software products. And extensively implemented UI components using JavaScript and Jquery.
- Built pluggable validation engine for both client-side and server-side. Implemented template-based report component on top of Microsoft's Open XML SDK by following Abstract Factory Pattern and Bridge Pattern.
- Created WCF Services with Dual security over different protocols (TCP and HTTP). And providing leadership and mentor junior engineers in developing their skills to ensure career development and succession planning.

**Eminent Business Solutions** 

Apr 2010 - Apr 2012

#### **Software Engineer**

- Enhanced and maintained a large web application used for employment testing and assessments.
- Created a user role based security system. Built an employee assessment system.
- Deployed software to production.

# **SKILLS**

\*

#### Microsoft Node JS \* \* C# **Express** \* ASP.NET CORE \* HAPI JS \* ASP.NET MVC MEAN Stack

*	WCF	*	Electron
*	Entity Framework	*	Bitcoin
*	LINQ		

# **Client Side**

*	Javascript + ES6
*	Typescript
*	React, Redux
*	GraphQL
*	Angular 1.0
*	Knockout JS
*	HTML 5, CSS 3, SASS
*	Bootstrap 4.0

# **Storage**

ASP.NET WEB API

- \* Mongo DB \* Dynamo DB
- \* Redis

# **Testing**

*	Mocha
*	Chai

**RESTIFY** 

- Enzyme Cucumber
- **PACT**

#### **Software Configuration**

- Webpack
- \* Gulp
- **Jenkins**
- \* Docker
- SonarQube
- Istanbul

# **PORTFOLIO**

Wavex Feb 2018 - Sep 2018

#### **Photon Infotech Pvt Ltd**

Wavex is a B2B single page web application to manage campaigns and offers for e-commerce vendors.

- \* Responsible for creating application boilerplate, middleware, validation library and other front-end components.
- \* Interacting with business analysts to convert business requirements into stories.
- \* Responsible to manage the team of 4 members and mentor them to improve the development.
- \* Responsible for creating unit test cases for front-end code using Mocha, Chai, and Enzyme.
- \* Responsible for creating unit test cases and contract testing for microservices.
- \* Responsible for creating functional test cases by using Cucumber.
- \* Responsible for deploying the code into production and non-production environments.
- \* Responsible for Jenkins and Docker configuration for this application.

Express	Mongo DB	React	Redux	HTML 5	CSS 3	Bootstrap	Webpack
Mocha	Chai	Enzyme	Cucumber	PACT	Istanbul	SonarQube	Docker

Lynx Block Explorer Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

#### **Universal Power Systems Pvt Ltd**

Lynx (LYNX) is a secure crypto-currency with fast transaction speeds and low-transaction fees.

- \* Responsible for creating application boilerplate, middleware and front-end components using javascript.
- \* Interacting with business analysts to convert business requirements into stories.
- \* Responsible for converting PSD design into HTML and CSS.
- \* Responsible for deploying the code into production and non-production environments using Docker.

Express	Mongo DB	React	Redux	Webpack
Bitcoin Core	Docker	HTML 5	CSS 3	Bootstrap

Wap Studio Nov 2014 - Dec 2016

#### **Universal Power Systems Pvt Ltd**

Wap Studio is a web application for in-house team to easily create web pages targeting smartphone and feature phone users. We are creating web pages with Eros Now media contents and sell those contents via telecommunication operators in India and other countries.

Wap Studio is perfect for non-techies who are not familiar with the intricacies of web development and for designers who prefer to work visually as possible, without fighting with code.

- Responsible for creating various application layers, client-side custom components, and server-side components and validation library using design patterns and best practices.
- Interacting with product owners to gather business requirements.
- \* Responsible for writing unit test cases for Controllers and Repositories using Nunit.
- Responsible to manage the team of 4 members and mentor them to improve the development.
- Responsible for deploying the code into production and non-production environments on AWS.

ASP.NET MVC	WEB API	SQL SERVER 2008	Angular 1.0	HTML 5	CSS 3
LINQ	ADO.NET	Entity Framework	Javascript	Boostrap	Gulp

Aircel Microsite Jan 2014 - Oct 2014

#### **Universal Power Systems Pvt Ltd**

A micro wap portal that would offer Utility services (prepaid recharge, post pay bill pay, mobile internet plans), as well as Entertainment, based VAS service (Mobile Content, Dialler Tunes) to the user under one single umbrella. The user would be able to pay his post-paid bills, recharge his prepaid as well as search and activate CRBT.

- Responsible for creating various application layers, client-side custom components, and server-side components and validation library using design patterns and best practices.
- Interacting with product owners to gather business requirements.
- Responsible to manage the team of 2 members and mentor them to improve the development.
- Responsible for deploying the code into production and non-production environments.

ASP.NET MVC	WEB API	SQL SERVER 2008	Knockout	HTML 5	CSS 3
LINQ	ADO.NET	Entity Framework	Javascript	Boostrap	Gulp

IBox 5.0 May 2012 - Sep 2013

# **Ibox Technology Pvt Ltd**

IBox is a B2B single page web application for booking, managing, tracking shipping containers for the Mediterranean shipping company (MSC).

- Responsible for creating various application layers, client-side custom components, and server-side components and validation library using design patterns and best practices.
- Interacting with product owners to gather business requirements.
- Responsible to manage the team of 6 members and mentor them to improve the development.
- Responsible for deploying the code into production and non-production environments.

ASP.NET MVC	WCF	ORACLE	Knockout	HTML 5	CSS 3
LINQ	ADO.NET	Enterprise Library	Javascript	JQuery	Boostrap

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Engineering** 

Bharathidasan Institute of Technology, Trichy

Did BE in Computer Science and secured CGPA of 7.5

Diploma in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Sri Venkateswara Polytechnic College, Cheyyar

Did diploma in ECE and secured 93.6%

2007 - 2010 2005 - 2007